I cannot approve of this.
You could have
defeated them both,
and yet you allowed
them to escape.
It wouldn't be any fun
to kill them right away.
Rabbits should be driven into a corner
and killed at the height of their terror.
But you had to reveal
Berserker's Noble Phantasm.
You should have killed at
least one of them in exchange.
That won't be a problem.
There is no way to counter
Berserker's Noble Phantasm.
Yes.
Noble Phantasm...
Once every three
days, restoration.
Surely you didn't show
mercy to Emiya Shirou.
Of course I did.
I have to make him
suffer in Kiritsugu's place.
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
You're awake?
That's a good sign.
Oh, your injuries seem
to have healed already.
Finding the Will to Fight
T-Tohsaka...
What are you...
Wait, what did I do?
Pick one thing to
be surprised about.
I see.
I passed out, and you
carried me back here.
So you're not as
dumb as you look.
That's very interesting.
Well, goodbye.
Tohsaka...
I should have said
this earlier, but thanks.
Wait.
Why are you thanking me?
Well, you saved me, didn't you?
You shouldn't thank an enemy.
The Holy Grail War
is a fight to the death.
Then why didn't you kill me?
I-I just didn't feel like it!
Attacking someone
in their sleep isn't fair.
So it was a blunder on my part.
I lowered my guard, perhaps
because I'm more powerful.
You could say I have
some emotional flab.
Emotional flab?
Are you saying that you're fat?
You're such a funny boy!
Well, the next time we
meet, it will be as enemies.
So be prepared.
Are we finally
going home, Master?
We can't return
empty-handed, can we?
I have to make
amends for my blunder.
Where's Saber?
Saber, what are
you doing in here?
I have been resting.
I thought I should at least
get into peak condition.
Shirou, how are your injuries?
Everything's fine.
I'm glad.
I must say, I am impressed.
I did not expect you to
possess self-healing magic.
Shirou, regarding last night,
there is something I feel I must say.
I must ask that you, my Master,
refrain from such actions in the future.
What choice did I have?
You were in danger.
You would place so much confidence
in a Servant you've only just met?
We shook on it, didn't we?
Your words are gratifying
to me as a Servant.
However...
In the future, please
restrain yourself.
I would have you
win the Grail for me.
You want the Holy Grail, too?
Yes.
So that I might
fulfill my own wish.
We Servants are Heroic Spirits.
As a result of that fame, when
we make known our true identities,
we also reveal our weaknesses.
So you go by "Saber"
to hide your real name?
Yes.
The Grail summons
seven Servants,
each selected
based on their class.
Class? Like swordsman or bowman?
Yes.
The Grail prepares
seven vessels in advance
and summons Heroic Spirits from
all eras that match those vessels.
These are the seven classes:
Saber, Lancer,
Archer, Rider, Caster,
Assassin, and Berserker.
I get it.
As a hero, you were
proficient with a sword,
so you were summoned
into the Saber class.
But from a different perspective, that
skill is also the Saber class's drawback.
Drawback?
Say you were faced with an opponent more
skilled than you in close-quarters combat.
What would you do?
Well, if I couldn't
win head-on...
I'd have to resort to a more
underhanded approach.
Exactly.
In addition, we possess what
are called "Noble Phantasms".
Lancer's spear, Archer's bow, and my
sword are all examples of Noble Phantasms.
Noble Phantasms are
Servants' trump cards.
However, a significant amount of
mana is required for their activation.
In other words, you can't
use them all the time?
That is correct.
What's more, a
Servant must call out the
Noble Phantasm's true
name when activating it,
so they run the risk of
revealing their identity.
Oh, so that's why you
make your sword invisible.
Shirou, I have a favor
to ask related to that.
It concerns my true name.
Normally, a Servant
reveals their identity to
their Master so they
can formulate a strategy.
However, you are
unskilled as a mage.
There is a chance that an experienced
mage could read your thoughts.
So I...
So you can't reveal
your name to me.
I understand.
I'll leave your Noble
Phantasm's use to your discretion.
Now that that's settled,
let's have breakfast.
Before I forget, where did
those clothes come from?
Rin gave them to me.
She said that since I cannot
dematerialize, I require ordinary clothes.
So she wears prim and
proper outfits like that...
DO NOT ENTER
It's faint, but I
sense mana residue.
Which means that
was no simple gas leak.
How could they
involve civilians in this?
I'm sorry.
Masters are supposed
to replenish their
Servants, but since I'm
such a novice, I can't.
I can minimize my mana
expenditure by sleeping.
Homurahara Academy
Archery Dojo
Hello, Emiya residence.
Hey, Fujimura here!
Fuji-nee?
What is it? I'm a
little busy right now.
Well, so am I!
I'm giving up my day
off for my students.
Anyway, make me lunch and
bring it to the archery dojo ASAP!
Over!
Huh?
Look, Saber...
Aren't Masters supposed
to avoid attracting attention?
I don't think we'll get a repeat
of last night in broad daylight.
But there is always a
possibility, however small.
It wouldn't be safe to allow
you to walk outside on your own.
Saber, if someone tries to talk to you,
just shake your head without replying.
It'd be best for you to act
like you don't know Japanese.
Saber?
I can sense residual mana.
Something feels off, but it
doesn't seem to pose any danger.
I said it was safe, didn't I?
Hey.
I'm here with
lunch for Fuji-nee.
Would you mind
calling her for me?
Ah, sure.
Boy, am I glad to see you.
You got her lunch?
Fujimura-sensei's been a handful. When
she's hungry, she gets all high-strung.
Why didn't you check first thing in the
morning to see if she'd brought lunch?
Well, I was kinda
worn out myself.
Shinji again? Where is he today?
Playing hooky. I think
he has a new girlfriend.
But anyway, Emiya...
Who was that woman out front?
She was gorgeous. Is
she a friend of yours?
Um, it's kind of complicated.
"Was"?
Kuzuki-sensei!
Emiya?
She's an acquaintance of mine.
She's sort of here to
check out the school.
We've never had a student
from overseas before.
If she enrolled, she'd
be an object of curiosity.
You should look
out for her, Emiya.
Yes, sir.
Incidentally, Emiya...
Outdoor shoes are forbidden
in the school building.
Shirou, about that instructor...
Did you sense something
about Kuzuki-sensei?
Not exactly. At first, he struck
me as being more than he seemed.
But he is not a mage,
nor does he smell of blood.
If Kuzuki-sensei turned out
to be a mage, I'd be shocked.
But what do you mean,
"more than he seemed"?
His breathing was exceedingly
natural and composed.
Frankly, I was quite impressed.
Even his gait was
perfectly efficient.
His pupils must be at ease
with such a man as their teacher.
Shall we proceed
to the next location?
Wait, you want to go
all around the school?
Yes, until I have
ascertained that it is safe.
I'm exhausted.
Huh? Emiya?
You're still at school?
You guys finish already?
Yeah, we're wrapping
up early today.
Ah. Well, keep up the hard work.
Hey, Emiya...
Will you ever come
back to the archery club?
It sounds like Fujimura-sensei
is trying to talk you into it,
but where do you stand?
Well...
I'm thinking of giving it another
shot once I get things sorted out.
You are?
That's a bit surprising.
Surprising?
From the minute you joined,
you were so good it was scary.
But it always seemed like you
weren't interested in hitting the target.
Or maybe you didn't
have the desire to.
I just assumed you quit
because you got bored.
It's like you have no
desire for anything.
Really?
I'm not saying you should be like
Shinji, but why not try to have some fun?
Man...
If a fellow student's worrying
about me, it must be really bad.
I mean, you never laugh, Emiya.
Remember training camp?
When we were all having
fun, you were the only one
who didn't so much as
chuckle at my best material.
Yeah...
I'm still holding a grudge.
Well, I need to drop by the faculty
office, so I'll see you tomorrow.
Mitsuzuri...
That girl's been following us.
Do you know her, Senpai?
Yeah, she's an old
acquaintance of my dad's.
Of Kiritsugu-san's?
She came to visit
Kiritsugu-san, then?
That's right.
She'll be staying at my place
for a while, so be nice to her.
Staying at your place?
You're shacking up with her?
We aren't shacking up.
Saber will only be
staying for a little while.
She's called Saber-san?
Yeah. I'd really appreciate it if you'd
try to be friends with her, Sakura.
Sure, I can do that.
Fujimura-sensei!
Are you giving her your
approval to stay, Fujimura-sensei?
As a teacher, I'd say
it's out of the question,
but I can't turn away a girl who's
come here to see Kiritsugu-san, so...
Sure, why not?
Just think of it as a homestay!
Temperatures are
expected to fall again tonight.
And here I'd pulled out all
the stops for this dinner...
Please exercise
caution when driving.
Sakura didn't
come to help, either.
Up next, we have
the weather report.
Fuji-nee, it's getting late.
Mind walking Sakura home?
Good evening.
- Now for tomorrow's forecast.
- Fuji-nee?
The Japanese islands are under a strong,
wintry pressure-distribution pattern.
It looks like this may bring nasty
weather with a focus on northern Japan.
Hello?
Didn't you hear me,
Fujimura-sensei?
Let's take a look at how the
clouds have moved since yesterday.
Sorry, request denied.
I won't be able to walk
Sakura-chan home for a while.
The small clouds that had
formed over the Sea of Japan
Why not?
And northern Japan are moving
to the east, toward the sea.
Because starting today,
I'll be staying here too.
Huh?
Care to join me, Sakura-chan?
I can call your
folks, so don't worry.
Y-Yes! Please!
I can always count on
you, Fujimura-sensei!
E-Eh?
Okay! Let's use the tatami
mat room in the back.
There are lots of
spare mattresses.
You don't mind, do
you, Saber-chan?
What kind of incense is this?
A witch's potion, most likely.
Possibly a poison
meant to destroy love.
In which case, we're
dealing with a woman?
Her resentment must be deep-rooted
for her to still act on it as a Servant.
Enough talk. Let's
open the windows.
The flow is toward
Ryuudou Temple?
Yes, the stolen life force is all
flowing toward the mountains.
The culprit behind the coma
incidents is probably Caster.
A witch inhabiting
Ryuudou Temple, huh?
That means we made
a mistake last night.
A mistake?
Fighting Berserker
to a draw, you mean?
I think that was the
optimal outcome.
I'm not so sure.
If Caster's spread such a wide net,
she must have observed last night's battle.
And yet we tipped our hand while
failing to defeat our opponents.
Perhaps.
We'll track Caster.
You can still sense her, right?
We'll put an end to this before
she can flee to Ryuudou Temple.
I thought your policy was to avoid
things that you know are beyond you.
It still is.
But don't you think
this is a special case?
You won't be satisfied
until you start a fight, huh?
You're ignoring an easily defeated opponent
and going after the most difficult one.
It's fine.
We can take him out
whenever we want.
I'm just choosing to ignore him as
long as he stays hidden at home.
Then what if Emiya
Shirou comes to you,
still choosing to ignore
the fact that he is a Master?
I'll kill him.
I'll show no quarter to anyone
who doesn't understand that.
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
Sakura and I have
broken the ice.
I know my brother
better than anyone.
No. I will not give you
the Command Spells.
Just prepare yourself, Shirou!
I shall grant you
a merciful death.
Dancing After School
Next Time